rwjf.org 2019-04-01

# Privacy Policy - RWJF

**Last updated:   May 18, 2018**

### 1.   Introduction.

This Privacy Policy (“Privacy Policy”) describes (a) how the Robert Wood Johnson Foundation (the “Foundation,” “we,” “us,” or “our”), either directly or through Service Providers (as defined below), collects information from you in connection with your use of the Sites (as defined below), (b) how we use and disclosure your information, and (c) the choices available to you regarding our use of your information and how you can access and update this information.

In the event any of the individual Sites has additional privacy terms, whether posted by us or the owner/administrator of the Site in question, your use of such Site also is subject to such privacy policy(ies). This Privacy Policy does not apply to the information collected through our grant application or review process, which is subject to a separate privacy policy _https://www.rwjf.org/en/privacy-policy-grant.html_.

As used in this Privacy Policy, the terms “ **Service Providers”** means third-party service providers who provide certain services to us (e.g., analytics, applications, hosting, software maintenance, satisfaction surveys, database maintenance, etc.) related to the Sites, and “ **Sites** ” means: (a) our website located at [_www.rwjf.org_](http://www.rwjf.org/)(the “ **Website** ”) and (b) certain other websites, blogs, online communities, social media platforms, and other services we may provide from time to time that link to this Privacy Policy, however such Sites are accessed or used, whether via personal computers, mobile devices, or otherwise.

By using the Sites, you agree to the collection, use, and disclosure of your information as described in this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, please do not use the Sites.

We reserve the right to modify or amend the terms of this Privacy Policy from time to time without notice.  Your continued use of the Sites following the posting of changes to this Privacy Policy will mean you accept those changes.

If you have questions or complaints regarding our Privacy Policy or practices, please contact us at:

U.S. Toll Free:  (877) 843-7953  

International: +1 609 627 6000 

Email:     [ _privacy@rwjf.org_](mailto:privacy@rwjf.org)

### 2.   How we collect your information.

We collect information related to you and your use of the Sites in the following ways:

**A.     Information you provide to us.**

  * Registration – In order to use some features of certain of the Sites, you must first complete a registration form. During registration, you may be asked to provide personally identifiable information and contact information (e.g., name, organizational affiliation, email and postal addresses, Twitter handle, etc.). If information requested is marked as “optional,” you are not required to provide that information in order to complete the registration process.
  * Email Subscription – In order to subscribe to certain of our email mailing lists you must complete a registration form. During registration, you may be asked to provide personally identifiable information and contact information (e.g., name, organizational affiliation, email and postal addresses, Twitter handle, etc.). If information requested is marked as “optional,” you are not required to provide that information in order to complete the registration process. Subscriptions to our email mailing lists must be confirmed by clicking on a link we will send to you via the email address you provide to us.
  * Ordering Publications – When you order a publication from one of the Sites, you will need to provide contact/shipping information (e.g., name, organizational affiliation, and email and postal addresses).
  * Interests – In order to facilitate your interaction with the Sites you may be asked to, and may wish to, provide information about your personal interests.
  * Surveys/Contests – From time to time, we may conduct online surveys on topics related to our programs or the Sites or conduct contests regarding the same. If you choose to participate in such a survey or a contest, you will be required to provide certain information to participate (e.g., name, organizational affiliation, email and postal addresses, Twitter handle, etc.). Participation in these surveys and contests is voluntary.
  * Contacting Us – You may choose to contact us, for example, to obtain technical support or provide feedback on the Site. We may collect any information you choose to provide when you communicate with us.

We may combine all of this data, along with data provided from your use of the Site as outlined below and other sources to offer you services and for the purposes described below.

### B.   Information collected from your use of the Sites.

  * Cookies and Other Technologies – We and certain of our Service Providers use cookies and other technologies, including web beacons and pixel tags, to passively collect information from you about you and your use of the Sites. This information may include: your Internet Protocol (IP) address, your location information, your device type, your browser type, your computer or device's operating system, the date/time you arrived on a Site, your internet service provider (ISP), the website or email address from which you arrived at the Site, your browsing destination after you leave the Site, and your actions on the Site itself, including the content you visited, clicked on, or shared on social media. See _[www.adobe.com/privacy/analytics.html](http://www.adobe.com/privacy/analytics.html) _for additional examples of the types of information that may be collected from your use of the Sites.
  * We and certain of our Service Providers also may use similar technologies in our email communications to let us know which emails and links have been opened by recipients. This allows us to, among other things, gauge the effectiveness of our customer communications and marketing campaigns.
  * You may be able to control the use of cookies using your browser settings. If you reject cookies, you may still use the Sites, but your ability to use some features or areas of the Sites may be limited. Turning off the browser's cookies will prevent web beacons from tracking your specific activity. The web beacon may still record an anonymous visit from your IP address, but unique information will not be recorded. However, if you are a subscriber to one of our email mailing lists and visit a Site by clicking a link in an email from us, we will be able to determine your identity even if you have turned off your browser’s cookies.
  * You may opt out of cookies provided by our Service Provider Adobe by following the instructions located at _[www.adobe.com/privacy/opt-out.html#4](http://www.adobe.com/privacy/opt-out.html#4) _and of cookies provided on our Sites by other Service Providers who are members of the Digital Advertising Alliance program by following the instructions located at _[www.aboutads.info/choices/](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/)_. You can find more information about cookies at [_www.allaboutcookies.org_](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).
  * Information collected by us by cookies and other technologies generally is not linked to your personally identifiable information. However, once you set up an account with of our Sites, the de-identified information associated with you may be linked to your user account and become personally identifiable information. We will use this information only as provided in this Privacy Policy.
  * _Local Storage Objects and Advertising_ – We use Local Storage Objects (“ **LSOs** ”), such as HTML5, to store content information and preferences. Service Providers with which we engage to provide certain features on our Sites or to display advertising based upon your web browsing activity use LSOs such as HTML5 or Flash to collect and store information. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5 LSOs. To manage Flash LSOs please see the information located at [_www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html_](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html) _._
  * _Behavioral Targeting/Re-Targeting_ – We use a third-party advertising network to either display advertising on our Sites or to manage our advertising on other websites. Our advertising network Service Providers use cookies and Web beacons to collect non-personally identifiable information about your activities on our Sites and other websites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests. If you do not want this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by clicking here: _[www.networkadvertising.org/choices/#completed](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/#completed)_. Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising entirely. You will continue to receive generic ads. __
  * _Social Media Widgets_ – Our Sites often include Social Media Features, such as the Facebook “Like” button and Widgets, such as the “Share” this button or interactive mini- programs that run on our Sites. These features may collect information, such as your IP address, which page you are visiting on our Sites, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third-party or hosted directly on our Sites. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it. Please review these privacy policies carefully. __

### 3.   How We Use the Information Collected.

We use the information collected from you for the following purposes:

  * to provide you with information about events, activities, opportunities, products, or services that might be of interest to you;
  * to respond to your inquiries and to provide you with customer support;
  * to assist in managing your account;
  * to conduct or facilitate surveys;
  * to maintain and administer the Sites;
  * to customize your experience, content, advertising, or homepage on the Sites, including providing engaging and consistent experiences across the Sites and providing you with more relevant products, services, or content;
  * to enforce the terms of use for the Sites or this Privacy Policy;
  * to generate aggregate statistical studies to analyze how the Sites are used, to gauge efficiency of email communications, and to conduct research which may be used in marketing our services to you or to third parties;
  * to deliver products or services to you; and
  * for any other purpose(s) described to you at the time you provide your information to us.

We will retain information collected from you for the duration of your relationship with us or as necessary to provide services that you request, comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements

### **4.    How We Share the Information Collected.**

We may share the information collected from you as follows:

  * with Service Providers that assist us in the provision of Services to you;
  * with our non-profit and for-profit funding or grant partners or other strategic partners when it is related to events, activities, opportunities, products, or services that might be of interest to you;
  * to conform or comply with the law;
  * if we have a good faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a lawful court order, government investigation, or subpoena, or is necessary and appropriate to cooperate with investigations by law enforcement or regulatory authorities or to participate or cooperate with a judicial proceeding;
  * to enforce applicable terms and conditions of the Sites;
  * in urgent circumstances, to protect the safety of persons or property, including but not limited to, the Sites; and
  * if we merge with or are acquired by another entity, undergo a re-organization with an entity, and/or in the event that we sell (or propose to sell) any property, business, or assets to an entity, we may disclose your information to such entity. If we undergo bankruptcy or liquidation proceedings, we may disclose your information to the entity managing our assets such as a receiver, to the court overseeing the proceedings, or as directed by such court.

We also may share information in an aggregated non-personally identifiable manner with third parties and such third parties may further share such aggregated non-personally identifiable information in connection with their own marketing, products, and services.

We will ask for your consent before using information for a purpose other than those permitted by this Privacy Policy.

### **5.    The General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).**

The GDPR is a European regulation concerning the use and processing of personal information. We are committed to processing the information of EU visitors to our Sites in compliance with the GDPR upon its effectiveness on May 25, 2018.

The applicable legal basis for which we process your information for the specific purposes listed above, include the following:

  * We have a legitimate interest in communicating with you and managing our interactions with your regarding our products and services.
  * In specific circumstances, we may need to process your information to comply with an applicable law or regulation. Where we process your information to meet our legal obligations, you will likely not be permitted to object to this processing activity, but you will usually have the right to access or review this information unless it would impede our legal obligations.

We will use reasonable efforts to timely respond to any requests by you to exercise your rights under the GDPR:

  * You have the right to see and get a copy of information, including an electronic copy that we have about you;   

  * You have the right to ask us to make any corrections to inaccurate or incomplete Personal Data we have about you;                   

  * You can also request that we erase your Personal Data when it is no longer needed for the purposes for which you provided it;  

  * You may ask us to restrict how we process your Personal Data to certain limited purposes where erasure is not possible;  

  * In certain circumstances you may be able to request that we send a copy of your Personal Data to a third party of your choosing; and  

  * You can object to processing of your personal information based on the Foundation’s legitimate interest (or those of a third party) to use it and there is something about your particular situation that causes you to object to such processing.

To exercise any of these rights, please contact us at the information provided above. You also have the right to lodge a complaint with the supervisory authority where you believe that your rights have been violated.

We hold your information and use it as described in this Privacy Policy and will use reasonable measures to ensure that your personal information is only transferred to third parties who also maintain at least the standard of protection required under the GDPR.

The Sites are owned and operated in the United States. Your use of the website will result in the collection, storage, and processing of your information in the United States and in any country to which we may transfer your information in the course of our business operations. If you are visiting this site from a country other than the United States, your information will cross an international boundary. The level of protection for your information in the United States may not be the same as the level of protection in your country. ****

### **6.    Children’s Personal Data.**

This site is not intended for or designed for individuals under the age of 16.  We do not knowingly collect information from any person under the age of 16.  ****

### **7.    Choice/Opt-out.**

If you no longer wish to receive communications from us, you may opt out of receiving these communications by visiting the Manage Your Subscriptions link in each of our Sites.

From time to time, it may be necessary for us to send out service-related announcements. For example, if one of our Sites is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we might send users an email notice regarding the suspension. Generally, users may not opt out of these communications unless they deactivate their account.

### 8.   Blogs.

Our Sites may offer publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personally identifiable information from a blog or community forum, contact us as noted above. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personally identifiable information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so.

Our blogs also may be managed by a third-party application that may require you to register to post a comment. We do not have access to or control of the information posted to such blogs. You will need to contact or login to the third-party application if you want the personally identifiable information that was posted to the comments section removed. To learn how the third-party application uses your information, please review its privacy policy.

### 9.   Links.

The Sites may contain links to other websites. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other websites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our Sites and to read the privacy policies of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected on the Sites.

### 10.   Security.

We have put in place appropriate physical, technical, and administrative procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. However, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is one hundred percent secure. You acknowledge that there are security and privacy limitations inherent to the Internet which are beyond our control, and the security, integrity, and privacy of any and all information and data exchanged between you and us through this Site cannot be guaranteed. We encourage you to be careful when using the Internet or transmitting data through a wireless network.

### 11.   Updating and Deleting Personally Identifiable Information; Data Retention.

If your personally identifiable information changes, or you want to stop receiving all email from us, use this [link](https://www.rwjf.org/en/manage-your-subscriptions.html) to manage your RWJF emails. If you no longer desire our services and you want your profile to be deleted from our systems please contact us at [_privacy@rwjf.org_](mailto:privacy@rwjf.org) and let us know you want your profile to be removed and be sure to include the email address associated with the profile to be removed.

We will retain information collected from you for the duration of your relationship with us or as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

### 12.   Your California Privacy Rights.

Pursuant to California Civil Code Section 1798.83, a California resident who has provided personally identifiable information to a business with whom he/she has established a business relationship has the right to request certain information regarding the disclosure of personally identifiable information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please use our Contact Us form, or write to us at: Robert Wood Johnson Foundation, 50 College Road East, Princeton, NJ 08540-6614, Attention: RWJF Web Privacy.

### **13.    Changes to this Privacy Policy.**

We may amend this Privacy Policy at any time in our sole discretion, subject to any applicable laws. It is your responsibility to review this Privacy Policy from time to time, to see if modifications have been made. Any modification is effective immediately upon posting on the applicable Site. Your continued use of the relevant Sites following modification of this Privacy Policy will be conclusively deemed to signify your acceptance of the modification. If we make any material changes to this Privacy Policy, we may notify you either by email (sent to the email address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on the applicable Site(s).
